Guide to the George A. Plimpton Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Reminiscences of Francis Taylor Pearsons Plimpton: oral history, 1967 In: Adlai E. Stevenson project. Oral History Research Office, Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Reminiscences of Francis Talor Pearsons Plimpton: oral history, 1981 In: Debevoise Plimpton Lyons & Gates project. Oral History Research Office, Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Francis T.P. Plimpton Papers, 1936-1981 Barnard Archives
- Series I: Correspondence and Personal Documents, 1841- 1936
  Series I consists primarily of correspondence addressed to or composed by George Plimpton. The series includes the correspondence catalogued previously as well as the uncatalogued materials labeled "General Correspondence."
  - Subseries 1: Cataloged Correspondence, 1876-1936
    The arrangement of the catalogued correspondence has not been modified. Although copies of some outgoing correspondence are included, the bulk of this subseries consists of incoming correspondence from a variety of persons and on a variety of topics including collecting, philanthropy, education and peace work. Also included are numerous notes, from prominent persons, thanking Plimpton for copies of the books he authored. Some correspondence is to and from Frances Taylor Pearsons, George Plimpton's first wife. Extensive outgoing correspondence from George Plimpton to Frances, and to their son, Francis, can be found here as well.
    - Correspondents--List of Cataloged, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abbott-Ayedelotte, 1886-1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Babbott-Beresford, 1886-1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bertram-Brooks, 1886-1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Brown-Burgess, 1885-1929 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Burlingham-Butler,1895-1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cable-Carnegie, 1888-1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Choate-Coffin, 1897-1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Coffin-John Dewey, 1888-1936 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Dewey, Melvil-Dodge, 1879-1929 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Dodge-Duggan, 1892-1936 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Eames-Ely, 1897-1934 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Farham-Finley, 1892-1936 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Fish-French, 1892-1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Garrison-Gunsaulus, 1891-1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Hadley-Hart, 1889-1936 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Hart-Hazard, 1900-1930 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Hazard-Hobhouse, 1881-1929 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Hodges-Hyde, 1876-1936 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Iddings-Karpinski, 1889-1935 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Karpinski-Lamont, 1906-1936 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Lamont-Lindsay, 1879-1935 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lindsay- Low, 1890-1934 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lowell-Mansfield, 1886-1935 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - March-Matthews, 1886-1927 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Maxwell-Millet, 1890-1935 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Mills-Murray, 1889-1935 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Nelson-Page, 1892-1935 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Palmer-Peirce, 1889-1929 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Peirce-Pulsifer, 1892-1930 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Pupin-Reuling, 1900-1934 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Reynolds-Sadler, 1900-1936 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Sanborn-Seeger, 1894-1936 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Seelye-Simhovitch, 1876-1935 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Sinclair-Charles Sprague Smith, 1887- 1919 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Smith, David Eugene, 1901-1911, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Smith, David Eugene, 1914-1936, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Smith, Edward Curtis-Royall Bascom Smith, 1892- 1913 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Söderblom-Tarbell, 1892-1935 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Taylor-Villard, 1876-1935 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Wald-West, 1885-1932 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Whalen-James Southall Wilson, 1900- 1933 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Wilson, Woodrow-Yen, 1897-1935 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - George Arthur Plimpton
      - to Frances Taylor Pearsons Plimpton, 1891-1898, (3 folders) (Box 54, Folder 3 to 6)
      - to Francis T. P. Plimpton, 1912-1929 (4 folders) (Box 55, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Subseries 2: Uncataloged Correspondence and Personal Documents, 1841- 1936
    The previous arrangement of the uncatalogued "General Correspondence" has been maintained. The current arrangement has relocated to this subseries such material as George Arthur and Frances Taylor Pearson Plimpton's correspondence from their courtship period, the guest albums from their wedding and home, family travel diaries from trips to Europe, Japan, China, and Alaska, and additional family correspondence.
    Because Plimpton's personal and financial lives were far from distinct, much of the correspondence in this subseries overlaps thematically with correspondence in Series II, particularly correspondence regarding Plimpton's philanthropic endeavors and trustee work. Yet this subseries tends to contain more of Plimpton's personal demonstrations of support and letters of introduction for friends and former employees.
    - Frances T.P. Plimpton, 1891- 1896, (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1 to 6)
    - George A. Plimpton
      - Marriage, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Death of Frances T. P. Plimpton, 1900- 1901 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - General, 1892-1915, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 3 to 5)
      - General, 1916-1936, (7 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1 to 7)
      - Birthday--60th, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Birthday--80th, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - General, 1863-1935 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Guest Album--Home, 1893-1936 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Guest Album--Wedding, 1892 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Notebook of Language Scripts, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Family Correspondence
      - General, 1841- 1907, (4 folders) (Box 11, Folder 6 to 9)
      - General, 1908-1936, (8 folders) (Box 12, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Family Correspondence, (Includes printed material and photographs)
      - General, 1852-1930s, (4 folders) (Box 12, Folder 9 to 12)
      - Adams Family, 1907-1922 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Family Genealogy, 1852-1935 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Family Photographs, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Family Tree, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Hastings--Clearing House in Paris, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Travel
      - Europe--Diary of Sarah E. Pearsons, 1899 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Europe--Travel Images, 1899 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Japan, China, Alaska, 1918-1936 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence and Diary, 1885- 1923 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Oversize--Honorary Degrees, undated (Mapcase 14-H-07)
- Series II: Financial Correspondence and Records, 1888- 1936
  Although the documents in this series not only relate to a diverse array of issues and sometimes overlap significantly with material in other series, these documents nevertheless provide discrete snapshots of the more financial side of Plimpton's life. The series includes Plimpton's general financial correspondence as well as documents related to particular companies and individuals. Between 1900 and 1911, for example, Plimpton served as executor for the estates of Sarah Pearsons, the mother of his first wife, Frances, and his sister Priscilla. The series includes various versions of Plimpton's own wills.
  The series also includes Plimpton's account books and daily diaries. The forty-one personal diaries in the collection provide a window into Plimpton's daily activities and expenses during the last four decades of his life, illustrating not just whom Plimpton met on which days but also the rising cost of taxis and martinis over several decades. Plimpton's check stubs, checks, and receipts provide further insight into his financial activities between 1889 and 1935. Other materials in the financial series include correspondence relating to the loans and donations that Plimpton made to dozens of individuals and institutions.
  Finally, the series contains documents related to Plimpton's real estate holdings, including account books, payroll and payment records, letters to delinquent tenants, and receipts for repairs and other work. The Walpole materials stand out from the other real estate materials not just because of their scope but also because they include documents related less to Plimpton's ownership of the Walpole property than to his life and affairs in the town. The inclusion of the latter materials in this series honors the original arrangement.
  - Daily Agendas, 1890- 1934, (41 folders) (Box 14, Folder 1 to 41)
  - Personal Accounts
    - Account Books, 1888-1899, (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Check Stubs and Notes, 1899-1904, (3 folders) (Box 15, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Receipts and Cancelled Checks, 1935, (3 folders) (Box 16, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Correspondence, (Includes Records and Documents)
    - Ardsley Estates, Inc., 1917-1935 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - The Central Foundry Co., 1931-1936 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Conant, Richard Royce Estate, 1918 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - General, 1899-1914 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - General, 1915-1935, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Loans--General, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Loans--Outstanding, 1923-1936 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Macnaughton Family--Estate of Sarah Pearsons, 1899- 1916 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Macnaughton, James and Elizabeth P.--NY Wool Warehouse Co., 1898- 1913 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Pearsons Estate, 1900-1902 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Plimpton, Priscilla--Lewis Estate, 1905- 1906 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Wills, 1921-1935 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Philanthropic Work
    - Donations, 1927-1935, (5 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 2 to 6)
    - Wood, Wallace, 1907-1916 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Real Estate--Holyoke, Massachusetts
    - Highland Park, 1896-1920 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Highland Park--Account book, 1909-1920, (3 folders) (Box 19, Folder 3 to 5)
  - Real Estate--New York City
    - 25th Street, 1905-1911 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Park Avenue--Number 59, 61, 1927- 1932 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Park Avenue--Number 62-65, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Plimpton Building, 1909-1921, 1931 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 38th Street, 1929-1934 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - George A. Plimpton vs. Alfred and Helen Baruch, 1926- 1927 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Plimpton Corporation, 1925-1931 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Property Speculation, 1902-1935 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Real Estate and Personal Affairs--Walpole, Massachusetts
    - Donations and Public Life, 1901- 1934 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Fuller's Tavern, 1927 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Lewis Farm, 1902-1937, (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Vouchers, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Wooden Indian Theft--Reward Poster, 1921 (Box 52, Folder 25)
- Series III: Ginn and Company, 1877-1936
  This series contains extensive materials related to the operation of the publishing firm that Plimpton led for decades. Currently arranged as previously processed, the series includes correspondence, company reports, photographs, mailings, and other materials dating from 1877 to 1936. While documents dating before 1911 are grouped by year, most documents dating after 1911 are associated with the employee who wrote or received them.
  Because the company's employees became such close associates over decades of cooperation, not all of their correspondence relates immediately to the company's affairs; for example, some materials relate to Edwin Ginn's peace work and, after 1914, to Ginn's estate. Moreover, not all the materials involve Plimpton directly.
  Documents related to Lewis Parkhurst prove particularly illuminating; because the Boston-based Parkhurst served as the company's administrative leader for decades, his files contain numerous company memos, annual reports, and meeting minutes. Following Ginn's death in 1914, Parkhurst served as one of Ginn's executors.
  - General--Ephemera, 1877- 1911
    - Mailings and Leaflets (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Photographs, 1905 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Plaster cast of Edward Ginn (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and Records
    - General
      - Dated, 1877-1899 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Dated, 1900-1911, (7 folders) (Box 22, Folder 2 to 9)
    - Ambrose, Fred M., 1911 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Ginn, Edwin, 1911 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1911 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Laylander, Orange Judd, 1911 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1911 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Smith, Selden C., 1911 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Thomas, Richard S., 1911 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Thurber, Charles Herbert, 1911 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - General, 1912 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Ambrose, Fred H., 1912 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Gilson, T. W., 1912 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Ginn, Edwin, 1912 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1912 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Hodgdon, Frederick C., 1912 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Lawler, Thomas Bonaventure, 1912 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Laylander, Orange Judd, 1912 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1912, (2 folders) (Box 23, Folder 9 to 10)
    - Smith, Selden C., 1912 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Thomas, Richard S., 1912 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Thurber, Charles Herbert, 1912 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - General, 1913 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Ambrose, Fred H., 1913 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Gilson, T. W., 1913 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Ginn, Edwin, 1913 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Hall, Dana W., 1913 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1913 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Hodgdon, Frederick C., 1913 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Lawler, Thomas Bonaventure, 1913 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Laylander, Orange Judd, 1913 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1913, (2 folders) (Box 24, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Smith, Selden Cornelius, 1913 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Thomas, Richard S., 1913 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Thurber, Charles Herbert, 1913 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - General, 1914 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - General--A-Z, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Ambrose, Fred H., 1914 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Ayer, Flora H., 1914 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - DeWitt, Edgar A., 1914 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Gilson, T. W., 1914 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Ginn Estate, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Hall, Dana W., 1914 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Hickam, A. R., 1914 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Hill, Charlotte F., 1914 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Hodgdon, Frederick C., 1914 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Lawler, Thomas Bonaventure, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Laylander, Orange Judd, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Maxwell, C. J., 1914 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1914, (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Robeson, L. B., 1914 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Smith, Selden C., 1914 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Thomas, Richard S., 1914 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Thurber, Charles Herbert, 1914 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Weaver, Frank, 1914 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - General, 1915 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - General--A-Z, 1915, (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 10 to 11)
    - Ayer, Flora H., 1915 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Fernald, Reginald L., 1915 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Field, Walter T., 1915 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Ginn Estate, 1915 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Greeley, W. H., 1915 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Hill, Charlotte F., 1915 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1915 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Hughan, Evelyn W., 1915 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1915 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Robinson, Edward K., 1915 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Thurber, Charles Herbert, 1915 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - General, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - General--A-Z, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Ayer, Flora H., 1916 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - DeWitt, E. A., 1916 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Ginn Estate, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Hall, Dana W., 1916 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Hodgdon, Frederick C., 1916 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Hughan, Evelyn W., 1916 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Jouett, Mark R., Jr., 1916 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Miller, Hugo, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Robeson, L. B., 1916 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Robinson, Edward K., 1916 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Smith, Selden Cornelius, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Thomas, Richard S., 1916 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Thurber, Charles Hubert, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - General, 1917 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - DeWitt, E. A., 1917 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Ginn Estate, 1917 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1917 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Hodgdon, Frederick C., 1917 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Jouett, Mark R., Jr., 1917 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - London Office, 1917, (3 folders) (Box 28, Folder 6 to 8)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1917 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Robeson, L. B., 1917 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Swartz, J. W, 1917 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Thomas, Richard S., 1917 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Thurber, Charles Herbert, 1917 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - General
      - Dated, 1918- 1919, (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 14 to 15)
      - Dated, 1920-1923, (4 folders) (Box 29, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Balance Sheets, 1920-1928 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - "A History of Ginn and Company"--Draft, 1922- 1923 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Conway, H. P., 1923 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - DeWitt, Edgar A., 1923 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1923 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Hodgdon, Frederick C., 1923 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Jouett, Mark R., Jr., 1923 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Laylander, Orange Judd, 1923 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Miller, Norman C., 1923 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1923 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Priddy, A. L., 1923 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Robeson, L. B., 1923 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Smith, Selden Cornelius, 1923 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Swartz, J. W., 1923 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Thomas, Richard S., 1923 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Thurber, Charles Hubert, 1923 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Weed, LeRoy J., 1923 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - General, 1924 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - DeWitt, Edgar A., 1924 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Executive Committee, 1924 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1924 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Jouett, Mark R., Jr., 1924 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Kenerson, E.H., 1924 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Lawler, Thomas Bonaventure, 1924 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Miller, Norman C., 1924 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1924 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Priddy, A. L., 1924 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Robeson, L. B., 1924 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Smith, Selden Cornelius, 1924 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Swartz, J. W., 1924 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Thurber, Charles Hubert, 1924 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Weed, LeRoy J., 1924 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - General, 1925 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - DeWitt, Edgar A., 1925 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Hall, Dana W., 1925 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1925 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Hodgdon, Frederick C., 1925 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Jouett, Mark R., Jr., 1925 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Kenerson, E. H., 1925 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Lawler, Thomas Bonaventure, 1925 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Laylander, Orange Judd, 1925 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Miller, Norman C., 1925 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1925 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Priddy, A. L., 1925 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Robeson, L. B., 1925 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Smith, Selden Cornelius, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Swartz, J. W., 1925 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Thurber, Charles Hubert, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - General, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Conway, H. P., 1926 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - DeWitt, Edgar A., 1926 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Hall, Dana W., 1926 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Jencko, Millard, H., 1926 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Jouett, Mark R., Jr., 1926 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Kenerson, E. H., 1926 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Laylander, Orange Judd, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Miller, Norman C., 1926 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Priddy, A. L., 1926 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Robeson, L. B., 1926 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Smith, Selden Cornelius, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Swartz, J. W., 1926 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Thurber, Charles Hubert, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - General, 1927-1934, (3 folders) (Box 31, Folder 21 to 23)
    - General--The Ginn Sketchbook, 1933 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - DeWitt, Edgar A, 1934 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1934 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Jouett, Mark R., Jr., 1934 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Laylander, Orange Judd, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Lucas, Homer C., 1934 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Miller, Norman C., 1934 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Newell, S. W., 1934 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Priddy, A. L., 1934 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Smith, Selden Cornelius, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Stevens, Ernest N., 1934 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Thurber, Charles Hubert, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - General, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - DeWitt, Edgar A, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Ginn Estate, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Jouett, Mark R., Jr., 1935 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Lawler, Thomas Bonaventure, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Miller, Hugo, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Parkhurst, Lewis, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Priddy, A. L., 1935 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Stevens, Ernest N., 1935 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - General, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - DeWitt, Edgar A., 1936 (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Hilton, Henry Hoyt, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 23)
- Series IV: Organizations, 1889-1936
  Centering on Plimpton's organizational commitments both in the United States and abroad, the documents in this series were drawn together from materials originally arranged alphabetically in the uncatalogued "Subject File." Because subheadings and folder names were arranged alphabetically in both the previous and current arrangement, the folders retain similar names and accordingly retain their original order. Documents include correspondence and records related to such organizations as the American Academy of Political Science, to Plimpton's work in Japan and the Near East, to his peace work, and to his trusteeships at Phillips Exeter Academy and Union Theological Seminary.
  - Academy of Political Science
    - General, 1897- 1908, (5 folders) (Box 32, Folder 24 to 28)
    - General, 1909-1915, (8 folders) (Box 33, Folder 1 to 8)
    - General, 1916-1936, (9 folders) (Box 34, Folder 1 to 9)
  - American Philological Association, 1916- 1934 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Arizona Home School, 1928-1935 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Committees, Directorships, Trusteeships, 1897- 1936 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Honorary Degrees and Awards, 1894- 1929 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Invitations and Responses, 1896- 1936 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Japan
    - Correspondence, 1912- 1936, (3 folders) (Box 35, Folder 2 to 4)
    - Ephemera, 1935 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Photographs and Postcards, 1935 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Memberships, 1889-1936, (2 folders) (Box 36, Folder 1 to 2)
  - "Near East Relations"
    - Constantinople Women's College
      - Buildings, 1909-1936 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Committees, 1904-1930 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1913- 1928 (Box 36, Folder 5)
        - General--Plimpton's Personality, 1906- 1932 (Box 36, Folder 6)
        - Borden, Caroline, 1915-1924 (Box 36, Folder 7)
        - Patrick, Dr. Mary Mills, 1914-1935 (Box 36, Folder 8)
        - Trustee Affairs, 1900-1929, (2 folders) (Box 36, Folder 9 to 10)
      - Dedication, 1914 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Difficulties, 1904-1928 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Donations, 1912-1931 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Fundraising and Finance, 1920-1922, (2 folders) (Box 37, Folder 4 to 5)
      - History, 1906-1931 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Hospitality and Meetings, 1915-1918 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Istanbul Woman's College, 1935 (Box 37, Folder 8)